<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Personal Portfolio of Nate Rudolph</title>
    <link>https://naterudolph.com/categories/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Personal Portfolio of Nate Rudolph</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://naterudolph.com/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Margaret</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2008-12-04-dear-margaret/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2008-12-04-dear-margaret/</guid>
      <description>The sun set through the windows creating long golden shadows on the couch and end table next to it. The room had several windows that let the only light in. Dust danced through the columns of fading light as Alvin walked toward the couch and eased his way into its faded cushions. When his full weight finally creaked into place a small cloud of dust rose to meet the dancing ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Denali</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2009-01-15-denali/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2009-01-15-denali/</guid>
      <description>I doubt I&amp;rsquo;ll soon forget this image before me. An entire mountain range of snow capped cliffs that seem to float over the dried up river valley. Hundreds of acres of sand and rock lie interrupted by the narrow channels that remind you that this once was, and will be again in its season, a gigantic river fed from the glaciers that rule over the land with a royal defiance. Every one of their peaks beg to be conquered, but the clouds that dance around them makes the plea futile, because I know I&amp;rsquo;ll never touch that snow or plant a flag there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eatin&#39; Grapes</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2007-03-22-eatin-grapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2007-03-22-eatin-grapes/</guid>
      <description>I work at a vineyard. And the answer is no, we don&amp;rsquo;t stomp on the grapes. To my knowledge that is a dead tradition. I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked this numerous times, to which I always describe to my disappointed interviewer that we actually use an antique cedar press. Working at a vineyard seems to be a more interesting job than any old farm hand, but when it comes down to it, most of the work is the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kellen Gallery</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2011-01-14-kellen-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2011-01-14-kellen-gallery/</guid>
      <description>{% include imageEmbed.html align=&amp;ldquo;center&amp;rdquo; path=&amp;ldquo;kellenGallery/Parsons-Festival-1280x540.jpg&amp;rdquo; alt=&amp;ldquo;Exterior of New School building&amp;rdquo; %}
While studying at Parsons I worked as a gallery technician at the award-winning Sheila Johnson Design Center. I helped build the exhibition and worked with the artists to ensure that the specific requirements were met for exhibiting their work. This included numerous video, sound, and interactive installations.
{% include imageEmbed.html align=&amp;ldquo;center&amp;rdquo; path=&amp;ldquo;kellenGallery/1-1024x768.jpg&amp;rdquo; alt=&amp;ldquo;Projectors in art gallery&amp;rdquo; %} {% include imageEmbed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Tree Hill Internship</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2010-04-22-one-tree-hill-internship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2010-04-22-one-tree-hill-internship/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you’re walking into a class for the final exam. Everyone around you has been taking studying for the class for 6 years and will undoubtedly ace it. They laugh and engage in small talk as they lackadaisically sit for the exam. They even joke with the teacher as he passes out the test. When eyes fall on you however, the conversations are quieted or even silenced. They do so out of compassion, because everyone knows you haven’t studied, haven’t even been to the class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Home</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2009-10-07-road-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2009-10-07-road-home/</guid>
      <description>The dusty Arizona road reminded Ben of something from a sci-fi movie. Growing up he had always expected a UFO to appear from behind one of the giant stone arches. Most days he had hoped for it. The amber clouds reflected the last few minutes of the sun’s light across the dusty horizon.
 “God. This is beautiful,” Ben whispered, eyes locked on the road. “You didn’t have to come. They’ve got buses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer &#39;04</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2009-03-04-summer-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2009-03-04-summer-04/</guid>
      <description>The long country highway melted into the horizon. Windows down we could smell the hay as the wind ripped it from our hair, under our fingernails, down our shoes. Everything was golden. The dust in the air, the freshly cut fields, the sky and its ever-diminishing ruler. We drifted over the gentle hills in silence. We knew every rise and valley of this road. Every turn and pothole. The abrupt transition to gravel woke those sleeping, which was fine; it meant we were almost home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2007-01-22-sunrise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2007-01-22-sunrise/</guid>
      <description>The sun is just now showing though the trees in the horizon. The fog, which only minutes before had blanketed the entire field, was beginning to melt as the orange and purple fingers widened in the east. The barn that sat on the border between the ground and the sky was originally a dark red. Now it faded to an orange in the new light.
Once a month or so I gather the will power to not hit snooze and make it out to our front porch and watch the show.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Adventerous Life of Rudy Montgomery</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2008-01-01-the-adventerous-life-of-rudy-montgomery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2008-01-01-the-adventerous-life-of-rudy-montgomery/</guid>
      <description>Above all, Rudy was frugal. Which made him a rather lonely man. He worked from a desk in his kitchen, a locale that afforded all the amenities of any office building, without the necessity of a car: business card holder (for the unlikely drop in), name placard (for official-ness), a computer (for work), and a blender (for a cheap smoothie lunch).
Agatha, Rudy’s mother, was not as content with Rudy’s situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bus</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2008-01-01-the-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2008-01-01-the-bus/</guid>
      <description>The first time it happened on accident. Jackson wasn’t looking at the road and failed to avoid the gigantic puddle in front of the school. We were thrown from our seats when the bus thudded into the pothole and transformed from stupor to wonder as we watched the wave cascade over the windows.
Jackson would always hit the puddle after that day. The further back in the bus we sat the higher we flew, but some preferred to watch the water splatter against the tall windows in the front.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fall and Rise of Stan</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2008-09-29-the-fall-and-rise-of-stan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2008-09-29-the-fall-and-rise-of-stan/</guid>
      <description>Stan woke up with a bowl of half eaten cereal at his elbows.
 &amp;ldquo;You left that pizza in the oven last night.&amp;rdquo; Stan looked up to see a woman with frazzled hair wearing an oversized sweater.
&amp;ldquo;If I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gotten back early the whole building could have burnt down.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Sorry Jenny,&amp;rdquo; Stan replied. &amp;ldquo;I guess I fell asleep.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Of course you did. Why didn&amp;rsquo;t you take the pills?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Just forgot I guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inventor</title>
      <link>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2009-01-01-the-inventor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://naterudolph.com/posts/2009-01-01-the-inventor/</guid>
      <description>Jack liked to make things. His bedroom floor was covered in broken alarm clocks, old remote controls, anything that was deemed “supplies” by Grandpa Flaherty. His latest project was a helmet that told the wearer the current weather. From each hole the in the rusty colander sprouted bunches of wires that lead to headphones attached at the handles.
 “Jack, get inside. It’s rai-” Grandpa Flaherty called from the porch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>